export const GRAPHICDESIGNA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Graphic Design products that are sometimes three-dimensional are",
A: "calendars and citations",
B: "labels and cartoons",
C: "newspapers and posters",
D: "packages and containers",
answer: "D. packages and containers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A book binding method that allows sheets to be removed easily is",
A: "edition binding",
B: "perfect binding",
C: "side-stitched binding",
D: "saddle-stitched binding",
answer: "C. side-stitched binding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Ascenders and descenders are associated with",
A: "initial letters",
B: "lower case letters",
C: "trajan letters",
D: "upper case letters",
answer: "B. lower case letters",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following groups of colours can be referred to as analogous?",
A: "Black and white",
B: "Blue, red and green",
C: "Green and red",
D: "Red, orange and yellow",
answer: "D. Red, orange and yellow",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The last step in edition binding is",
A: "casing-in",
B: "collating",
C: "folding",
D: "trimming",
answer: "A. casing-in",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Binding cloth is normally used for",
A: "class registers",
B: "exercise books",
C: "hard cover books",
D: "soft cover books",
answer: "C. hard cover books",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following tools is used in screen printing?",
A: "Bone folder",
B: "Brayer",
C: "Spatula",
D: "Squeegee",
answer: "D. Squeegee",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The processes involved in single-section binding is",
A: "folding, collating, stitching",
B: "gathering, gluing, stamping",
C: "pressing, stamping, stitching",
D: "rounding, backing, lining",
answer: "A. folding, collating, stitching",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Printed booklets distributed during speech and prize giving days are",
A: "brochures",
B: "catalogues",
C: "magazines",
D: "pamphlets",
answer: "D. pamphlets",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The process whereby unwanted areas of a picture are removed is known as",
A: "bleeding",
B: "cropping",
C: "enlarging",
D: "trimming",
answer: "B. cropping",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A gauze-like material used on the spine of a book when binding is called",
A: "bandage",
B: "mesh",
C: "muslin",
D: "tarpaulin",
answer: "C. muslin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. One of the steps in multi-section binding is",
A: "gluing all the leaflets together",
B: "joining the pages with spiral cord",
C: "sewing the signatures onto one another",
D: "side stitching the signatures",
answer: "C. sewing the signatures onto one another",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Screens can be prepared by blocking them with",
A: "glue",
B: "lacquer",
C: "varnish",
D: "thinner",
answer: "A. glue",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Speeches made by characters in cartoon drawings are enclosed in",
A: "balloons",
B: "captions",
C: "panels",
D: "strips",
answer: "A. balloons",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following Graphic Design products has the widest coverage?",
A: "Billboards",
B: "Buntings",
C: "Calendars",
D: "Pennants",
answer: "A. Billboards",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following pairs of binding methods is mechanical?",
A: "Comb and spiral",
B: "Perfect and ring",
C: "Saddle stitched and perfect",
D: "Side stitched and case",
answer: "A. Comb and spiral",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Ammonium dichromate mixed with emulsion is used to",
A: "etch steel rollers for printing",
B: "print currency notes",
C: "sensitize screen for printing",
D: "transfer images onto silk screens",
answer: "C. sensitize screen for printing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Letter spacing in which parts of letters overlap each other is called",
A: "kerning",
B: "line spacing",
C: "sharing",
D: "word spacing",
answer: "C. sharing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following options is an example of relief printing?",
A: "Block printing",
B: "Direct printing",
C: "Lithographic printing",
D: "Mono printing",
answer: "A. Block printing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. In perspective drawing, closer objects appear",
A: "bigger",
B: "thinner",
C: "shorte",
D: "smaller",
answer: "A. bigger",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following tones of colour is printed first in multi-colour printing?",
A: "Darkest",
B: "Darker",
C: "Lighter",
D: "Lightest",
answer: "D. Lightest",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In the 12-point colour wheel, the colours between the primary and secondary are",
A: "complementaries",
B: "intermediaries",
C: "neutral colours",
D: "warm colours",
answer: "B. intermediaries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The illustration above on a package stands for",
A: "it is frozen",
B: "it is waterproof",
C: "keep it dry",
D: "keep it out of the sun",
answer: "C. keep it dry",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following Graphic Design products is a corporate identity mark?",
A: "Brochure",
B: "Catalogue",
C: "Logo",
D: "Magazine",
answer: "C. Logo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Tonal effects make drawn objects look",
A: "flat and real",
B: "flat and shiny",
C: "real and solid",
D: "solid and big",
answer: "C. real and solid",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following options is a simple method of reproducing a design?",
A: "Drawing",
B: "Painting",
C: "Sketching",
D: "Stenciling",
answer: "D. Stenciling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In which printing process is a brayer used?",
A: "Block",
B: "Gravure",
C: "Letter press",
D: "Screen printing",
answer: "D. Screen printing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A method of painting with diluted ink or paint is known as a",
A: "dichrome",
B: "graffiti",
C: "monochrome",
D: "wash",
answer: "D. wash",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Newly designed products are usually directed at",
A: "clients",
B: "customers",
C: "retailers",
D: "wholesalers",
answer: "B. customers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The early Egyptians form of writing is called",
A: "cuneiform",
B: "hieroglyphics",
C: "quadrata",
D: "sanskrit",
answer: "B. hieroglyphics",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following options describes reversed lettering?",
A: "Letters printed on pictures",
B: "Letters written to face opposite direction",
C: "Mixture of upper and lower case letters",
D: "White letters on a black background",
answer: "D. White letters on a black background",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Identify the name given to thin parallel lines drawn on layout to indicate body of a text",
A: "Comps",
B: "Greeking",
C: "Loops",
D: "Script",
answer: "B. Greeking",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Artist illustrate in books to",
A: "create pictorial forms for amusement",
B: "demonstrate drawing skills to the reader",
C: "emphasize points in the book",
D: "introduce some elements of realism",
answer: "C. emphasize points in the book",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Uncontrolled marbling is a form of monoprint because",
A: "kerosene alone can make colour float",
B: "only one print of the pattern can be made",
C: "only oil paint is used in marbling",
D: "one person can make a print at a time",
answer: "B. only one print of the pattern can be made",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Why should the size of a squeegee be slightly shorter than the screen frame?",
A: "To print interestin g and inlricate designs",
B: "To make the squeegee strong and firm",
C: "To facilitate easy movement of the squeegee",
D: "To prevent the squeegee from absorbing colour",
answer: "C. To facilitate easy movement of the squeegee",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Bold, italic, larger type faces and colour are methods of providing",
A: "balance",
B: "contrast",
C: "rhythm",
D: "unity",
answer: "B. contrast",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Text that is left-aligned is also called",
A: "centred",
B: "justified",
C: "left-rugged",
D: "right-rugged",
answer: "C. left-rugged",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. In designing, all white areas surrounding the main composition is considered to be",
A: "background",
B: "foreground",
C: "negative space",
D: "positive space",
answer: "C. negative space",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A faint design made in paper and visible only against light is known as",
A: "dandy roll",
B: "hologram",
C: "seal",
D: "watermark",
answer: "D. watermark",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A set of three colours equidistant to each other on the colour wheel forms a",
A: "tint",
B: "triad",
C: "triangle",
D: "trichrom",
answer: "B. triad",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]